Inventory of the George T. Beck Papers, 1869-1968
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
George T. Beck Papers
1869-1968
Beck, George T. (George Thornton), 1856-1943.
00059
19.12 cubic ft. (35 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
George T. Beck came to Wyoming in 1879, and was a sheep rancher, oil land developer, businessman, and politician in the Cody, Wyoming area. The collection contains correspondence and diaries of the Beck family, a manuscript for George Beck's autobiography, correspondence, journals and record books relating to his many business ventures, and printed material relating to his political and business careers.
Biography of George T. Beck
George Washington Thornton Beck was a Wyoming sheep rancher, oil land developer, businessman, and politician. Born 28 July 1856 near Lexington, Kentucky, Beck was the son of James Burnie Beck and a collateral descendant of George Washington. Beck studied civil engineering at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in New York. In 1877 he headed west, eventually settling in northern Wyoming near present-day Sheridan. He owned a large sheep operation and was active as a mining engineer. In 1895 Beck laid out the city of Cody with his friend Colonel William F. (Buffalo Bill) Cody. Together they also formed the Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company. Later Beck built and operated the Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company and helped develop surrounding oil fields. Beck was the first member of the Wyoming territorial council from Johnson County and the president of the last territorial council. In 1902 he made an unsuccessful run for the governorship, but earned the nickname "Governor" nonetheless. He served as mayor of Cody in 1903 and was a member of the Wyoming State Senate from 1913-1917. He also served as a six time delegate to the Democratic National Convention. In 1897 Beck married Daisy M. Sorenson. Together they had three children: George T. Beck, Jr., Jane Beck Johnson, and Betty Beck Roberson. George Beck died 1 December 1943 in Cody.
Scope and Content
The George T. Beck Papers, 1869-1968, include a large number of journals and record books relating to Beck's many business ventures. The collection contains records of the Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company the Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company, and other associations and organizations. The Legal Documents contain material relating to various court cases and land claims. Correspondence contains a mixture of personal, business, and politically-related correspondence. Diaries and Personal Papers include George Beck's diaries from 1889-1942. These diaries record daily happenings around the Beck residence in Cody and with Beck's business interests. This series also includes correspondence and financial receipts belonging to Christian Inhelder. Political Papers contain material belonging to George Beck's father, Senator James Beck of Kentucky, and also include documents relating to the many Democratic Conventions George Beck attended. Printed Material contains newspaper clippings relating to Beck's political and business careers. Maps of Wyoming and surrounding areas are included, as well as surveys of land around Cody and blueprints of several construction sites.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by George T. Beck at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The George T. Beck Papers were donated to the University of Wyoming in 1947 and 1966 by Daisy Sorenson Beck and her children.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of select material from this collection are available at http://digitalcollections.uwyo.edu:8180/luna/servlet/uwydbuwy~111~111.
Access Terms
Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917.; Roberson, Betty Beck.; Beck, James B. (James Burnie), 1822-1890.; George T. Beck Refinery.; Park County Fair Association (Wyo); Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company.; Shoshone Irrigation Company.; Democratic National Convention.; Water resources development--Wyoming--Park County.; Electric utilities--Wyoming--Park County.; Cuba -- History -- 1810-1899.; Wyoming -- Politics and government.; Cody (Wyo.); Park County (Wyo.); Wyoming -- History--To 1889.; Wyoming -- History --1890-1918.; Wyoming -- History -- 1919-1945.; Wyoming -- History -- 1946-; Diaries.; Business records.; Photographs.; Businessmen.; Beck family
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Business, Industry, Labor, and Commerce; Ranching; Water and Water Rights; Politics, Government, and Law; City Planning; Overland Journeys to the Western United States; Pioneers; Wyoming
Container List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1944
  - Sub-series I. George T. Beck Correspondence, 1869-1944
    - Correspondence, 1869-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1-21)
    - Correspondence, 1899-1904 (Box 2, Folder 1-18)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1912 (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1925 (Box 4, Folder 1-17)
    - Correspondence, 1926-1937 (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1944 (Box 6, Folder 1-7,)
  - Sub-series II. Beck Family Correspondence, 1875-1942
    - Beck, Betty, 1910-1933 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Beck, George T. Jr., 1937-1942 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Beck, James B., 1875-1889 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Beck, Jane T., 1909-1938 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Cody, William F., 1896-1905 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Nelson T, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Rumsey, Bronson, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Sorenson (Beck), Daisy, 1896-1942 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Series II. Diaries and Personal Papers, 1876-1968
  - Address Books (3), 1906-1908 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Autobiographical Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Autobiography -- Beck, George T., 1923 (Box 7, Folder 3-6)
  - Beck, George T. Jr. -- Speech, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Material -- Beck, George T., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Certificates, 1889-1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Character Description -- Beck, George T., undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Diaries -- Beck, Betty Goodloe, 1906, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Diaries -- Beck, George T. Jr. --Trip to Havana, Cuba with Father, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Diaries -- Beck, George T., 1892, 1902, 1904, 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Diaries -- Beck, George T., 1916-1930 (Box 8)
  - Diaries -- Beck, George T., 1931-1942 (Box 9)
  - Genealogy, 1887, 1889 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Inhelder, Christian -- Correspondence, 1885 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Inhelder, Christian --Receipts and Mortgages -- Originals, 1880-1890 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Inhelder, Christian -- Receipts and Mortgages -- Photocopies, 1880-1890 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts, 1896-1943 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous -- Club Memberships, Licenses etc., 1902-1939 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks, 1916, 1927, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Phrenological Character, 1876 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series III. Business and Legal Records, 1879-1942
  - Sub-series I. Business Records, 1879-1942
    - Beck, James B. -- Book Listing of Land Ownership in Missouri. Wisconsin, and Minnesota, 1879 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - George T. Beck Refinery, 1937-1942 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - George T. Beck -- Order Book, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Beckton Mill, 1883-1888 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Beckton Mill -- Ledger -- Accounts of Construction and Journal Entries, 1883-1888 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Beck Sulphur Placer and West Sulphur Placer, 1903-1923 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Big Horn Basin Development Company, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Big Horn County, 1895 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Big Horn County School District No. 6, 1897, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Buffalo Mill Company, 1887-1891 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Cody Canal Association, 1907, 1932, 1941 (Box 12)
    - Cody Club, 1901-1931 (Box 12)
    - Cody Garage Club, 1912-1913,1925 (Box 12)
    - Cody Golf Club, 1926-1931 (Box 12)
    - Cody Oil and Development Company, 1903-1904 (Box 12)
    - Cody Townsite Company, 1896-1910 (Box 12)
    - Cook House -- Ledger -- Accounts of Supplies and Invoice List, 1896, 1901 (Box 12)
    - County Assessments, 1902-1913 (Box 12)
    - First National Bank of Cody, undated (Box 12)
    - General Business Records, 1904-1941 (Box 12)
    - General Business Records -- Cash Book -- Personal Accounts, Deposits and Balances, 1911-1916 (Box 12)
    - General -- Daily Cash Counterbook -- Accounts of Cash Received and Paid, 1896 (Box 12)
    - General Business and Financial Records -- Day Book -- Business and Financial Records, 1881-1888 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General Business Records -- Day Book -- Daily Accounting of Money, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - General Business Records -- Drilling Account in Beaumont, Texas, 1917-1919 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - General Business Records -- Financial Reports, 1891,1896 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - General Business Records -- Ledger -- Accounts of Fruit, Cigars, and Candy, 1910-1916 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - General Business Records -- Financial Figures, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - General Business Records -- Journal -- Taxes, 1897-1925 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - General Business Records --Weekly Time Book, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - General Business Records -- Workmen's Time Book, 1890s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln Land Company, 1900-1915 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Park County Fair Association, 1912-1919 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Park County Fair Association, 1921-1928 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Park County Fair Association, 1932-1943 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Park County Fair Association, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Park County Fair Association -- Assignments, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Park County Fair Association -- Bank Records, 1923-1941 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Park County Fair Association -- Forms, 1915-1916 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Park County Fair Association -- Insurance Records, 1933-1942 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Park County Fair Association -- Printed Material, 1915-1924 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Pioneer Building: Account Book -- Insurance Policies and Receipts, 1903-1911 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Pioneer Building: Leases and Statements, 1907-1924 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Shoshone Electric Light And Power Company, 1904-1934 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Annual Reports, 1922-1929 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Bills, 1905-1934 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Cash Book -- Supplies and Expenses, 1909-1914 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Cash Book -- Cash Paid Out and Cash Received, 1911-1916 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Cash Book, 1911-1916 (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Cash Book -- Accounts of Merchandise, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Correspondence, 1905-1924 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Correspodence -- Westinghouse, 1905-1923 (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Day Book -- Agreements and Cancelled Checks, 1904-1905 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Development Report, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Electric Power Survey, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Index of Names -- A-Z, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Insurance, 1906-1934 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Journals -- Accounts, 1905-1925 (Box 18, Folder 7-9)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Ledger -- Index of Names and Merchandise, 1906-1907 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Ledger -- Accounts, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Ledger, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Meter Books, 1906-1910 (Box 19, Folder 3-10)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Notebook "Paid Out", 1907 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Shoshone Electric and Power Company -- Receipt Books, 1922-1925 (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Stock Book, 1905, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company -- Tax Records, 1909-1937 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Electric and Power Company -- Tax Records -- Water Appropriation Certificates, 1907, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company, 1895-1897 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company, 1894 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Shoshone Irrigation Company, 1898-1903 (Box 20, Folder 8-11)
    - Shoshone Irrigation Company, 1904-1908 (Box 21, Folder 1-5)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Contracts, 1896, 1901, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Shoshone Land and and Irrigation Company -- Check Book, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Shoshone Land and and Irrigation Company -- Day Books -- Financial Records, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Land and and Irrigation Company -- Day Books -- Financial Records, 1902-1903 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company --Field Notes, Construction Books, Miscellaneous (17), and History, 1893-1910 (Box 23, Folder 1-18)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Ledger of Financial Records, 1895-1897 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Ledger of Merchandise and Property Accounts, 1896-1902 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1896-1897 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Letter Press Books, 1897 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Letter Press Books, 1896 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Letter Press Book -- Beck, George T., Manager, 1896-1898 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Letter Press Book -- Elliot, D.H., Land Commissioner, 1897 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Manager's Book -- Merchandise Accounts, Receipts, and Bills, 1895-1896 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Payroll, 1896-1898 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Sales Register, 1903-1906 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Receipt Book, 1901 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Supply Book, 1896 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Shoshone Land and Irrigation Company -- Water Rights Contracts, 1896-1907 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Woodmen of the World -- Book of Ceremonies, 1918 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Modern Woodmen of America -- Pass Report Book -- Financial Records, 1910-1915 (Box 28, Folder 3-5)
    - Modern Woodmen of America -- Index of Names A-Z, 1908-1911 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series II. Legal Documents, 1884-1942
    - Beck Family Legal Documents -- Includes George T. Beck's Will, 1887-1929 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Milling/Lumber, 1880s-1937 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Mining, 1884-1911 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1886-1931 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Notices of Proposed Locations, 1897-1920 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Oil and Gas, 1903-1942 (Box 29, Folder 6-8)
    - Real Estate, 1885-1942 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
- Series IV. Political Papers, 1888-1938
  - Beck, James B. (Senator), 1885,1888 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Bills, 1890-1890 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Democratic Conventions --Correspondence, Platforms, 1896-1932 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Party Platforms, 1908 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts and Notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Petitions, 1908 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Poll Books, 1896-1898 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Printed Material, 1909-1923 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1890-1938 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Series V. Photographs and Audio-Visual Materials, 1880-1947
  - Beck, Betty Goodloe, 1899 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Beck, Daisy S., undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Beck, George T., 1889-1890 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Beck, George T., 1906-1936 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Beck, George T. -- Residence in Cody, Wyoming, 1920, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Beck, James Burnie and Jane Augusta Washington Thornton, no date (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Beck Refinery, 1897 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Boal, Horton, 1890 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Buffalo, Wyoming, 1888 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Burke, Major John M., undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Cody, Wyoming, 1899, 1903, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Cody Canal, 1895-1897 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Cody, William F. (Buffalo Bill), 1898-1906 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Ferry -- Jamestown to Newport, Rhode Island, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Iron Tail (Chief), undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, Jane Beck and Nelson T. and Family, 1930-1939 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Kingsford 1821 Stump, 1909 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Lakeview Canal, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Leitz, Joseph, circa 1895 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Negatives--Unidentified Soldier, ca. World War I, undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Oregon Basin, 1904, 1920, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Perkins, C.E., undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Picture Postcards, 1910-1947 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Schwoob, Thornton, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Sheridan County, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Shoshone Dam, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Sod House, 1885 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Stagecoach (Artwork), undated (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Thorn, William T, 1899 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified Landscape, undated (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Washington, George T. -- Seal, undated (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Whitney, Gertrude Payne, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Wildlife -- Elk and Mountain Goats Feeding During Winter, undated (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Phonograph Record - "A Personal Message from Franklin D. Roosevelt", 1932 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of George T. Beck -- Printing Plate, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Series VI. Printed Material, 1883-1957
  - Advertisements -- Ads for Machinery and Other Products, 1897-1932 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 1883-1938 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Catalog -- "American Miller", 1885-1886 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous -- Articles, Speeches, etc., 1902-1933 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1900-1943 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Programs and Invitations, 1874-1926 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Sons of the American Revolution -- Bulletins and Registers, 1891-1944 (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
  - Construction Blueprints -- Shoshone Electric Light and Power Company, Placer Claims, Cody Canal, etc., 1897-1913 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents -- Land Claims, Contracts, Elections and Stock Certificates, 1888-1910 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Maps and Surveys -- Wyoming and Colorado, and the United States, 1908, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - Newspapers, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 5)